## Pablo Sanchez Narro

sancheznarro.pablo@gmail.com — +44 7874932115 / +34 684710945 — • PabloSczn — • pablosanchezn — • pablosancheznarro.com

### **Profile**

Experienced Software Engineering BEng with a First-Class degree, fluent in **Spanish** and **English** (C2) and intermediate in **French** and **Italian** (B1). Strong 'get things done' attitude, exceptional ownership, and deep engineering fundamentals. Proven in managing complex software projects and leading dynamic teams to exceed development standards.

### **Education**

#### BEng (Hons), Software Engineering

2020-2024

Edinburgh Napier University, Edinburgh, UK

- Graduated with a first-class average of 80%.
- Dissertation: "Exploring Explainable AI (XAI) Methods for Enhancing Transparency in AI Models"
- Acquired skills in object-oriented programming, secure software design, concurrent programming and agile project management.

# **Professional Experience**

Software Engineer May 2024–Present

TaxCoder, Remote

- Joined a startup providing comprehensive tax support and expert accounting services through a cutting-edge online platform.
- Led the development of a web application using Python **Django**, **HTML5**, **CSS3**, **Bootstrap**, and **PostgreSQL** on **AWS**, driving product innovation and operational efficiencies.
- Managed a dynamic team of 3, instilling a culture of problem-solving, proactive development, and continuous learning.

QA Engineer Sep 2023–May 2024

Infographics UK Ltd, Edinburgh, UK

 Managed Azure DevOps and implemented automated QA testing using xUnit and Selenium, increasing product reliability and reducing manual testing tasks by 30%.

Part-time position during bachelor's I was offered due to outstanding performance during the internship.

### **Software Engineer Intern**

Jun 2022-Sep 2023

Infographics UK Ltd, Edinburgh, UK

- Enhanced application performance and resolved customer-reported bugs through optimized **C#** code development. Worked on the migration of a WPF App to Cross-Platform with .**NET MAUI**
- Participated in agile development cycles, utilizing **Scrum** methodologies and integrating with **MS DevOps** systems for efficient project management.

### **Technical Skills**

Languages & Frameworks: Python (Django, Flask), C#, Java, JavaScript (NodeJS, ExpressJS, ReactJS), C++, and basic Ada & Haskell

Tools & Platforms: Docker, AWS, Azure DevOps, GitHub, Linux, Kubernetes (basic), Ansible (basic)

Databases: PostgreSQL, SQL, MongoDB, NoSQL

Web Development: RESTful APIs, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, AJAX

Software Practices: CI/CD, Agile Methodologies (Scrum), DevOps, Automated Testing (xUnit, Selenium), Monitoring and

Alerting (Sentry)

## **Certifications**

### Microsoft Certified: Azure Al Engineer Associate (Al-102)

Jul 2024

- Learned all phases of **AI solutions development**, including requirements definition, design, development, deployment, integration, maintenance, performance tuning, and monitoring.
- Integrated AI capabilities in other applications and solutions using Python, C#, REST APIs, and SDKs.
- Implemented solutions for content moderation, computer vision, natural language processing, knowledge mining, document intelligence, and **generative AI**.